A Guide to the Furious Flower Poetry Center Records, 1990-2014: UA 0017
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Oversize, 2004-2012 (Box OV1)
  - Among Poets: Lucille Clifton Commemorative Exhibition panels, undated (Box OV2)
    - Thomas Sayers Ellis, poet, educator, and former member of the Dark Room Collective (2004), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 13)
    - Fred D' Aguiar, poet and educator (2004), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 14)
    - W. S. Merwin, poet and former Chancellor of the Academy of American Poets (2000),, 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 15)
    - Joanne Gabbin and Lynda Koolish, curators of the exhibit "Won't You Celebrate With Me" (2010), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 1)
    - Lucille Clifton with daughters Gillian and Alexia (2000), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 2)
    - Val Gray Ward, actor, director, and founder of the Kuumba Theater Company and Joanne Gabbin at the Clifton tribute at JMU (2010), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 3)
    - Kwame Dawes, poet, educator, and Cave Canem Faculty (2008), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 4)
    - Jericho Brown, poet and educator (2008), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 5)
    - Kelly Norman Ellis, Nikky Finney, Rachel Eliza Griffiths, Aisha Moon, Alexia Clifton, Gillian Clifton, Samantha Thornhill, Treasure Williams, and Tayari Jones at JMU (2010), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 6)
    - Quraysh Ali Lansana, poet and educator, and Joanne Gabbin at JMU (2010), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 7)
    - Lamont Steptoe, poet, photographer, and Vietnam veteran (2008), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 8)
    - Tayari Jones, author and speaker (2007), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 9)
    - Lucille with daughters, Alexia, Sidney, and Gillian (2000), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 10)
    - Kimberly Ellis, Joanne Gabbin, Rita Dove, Aisha Moon, and Rachel Eliza Griffiths at the Clifton tribute at JMU (2010), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 12)
    - Lucille (Sayles) Clifton with her father Sam Sayles, Sr. and Fred Clifton (circa 1957), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 13)
    - Alicia Ostriker, poet and author of important critical essay on Clifton (2007), 2012 (Box OV3, Folder 14)
    - Marilyn Nelson, Poet Laureate of Connecticut and Cave Canem Elder (2007), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 1)
    - C. D. Wright, taken at the Desert Nights, Rising Stars: the ASU Writers' Conference (2005), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 2)
    - Yusef Komunyakaa, Pulitzer Prize-winning poet and Cave Canem Faculty (2008), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 3)
    - Adrienne Rich (1929-2012), poet and former Chancellor of the Academy of American Poets (1978), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 4)
    - Cornelius Eady, poet and co-founder of Cave Canem (2003), 2012, 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 5)
    - Alfredteen Harrison, Civil Rights activist and co-convener of Unsettling Memories Conference (2004), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 6)
    - Unnamed healer at slave burial grounds in Natchez, Mississippi (2004), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 7)
    - Alice Walker, author, poet, and collector of quilts (2002), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 8)
    - Eugene Redmond, Amiri Baraka, Sonia Sanchez and Joanne Gabbin at 2004 Furious Flower Poetry Conference (2004), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 9)
    - Gordon Parks (1912-2006) photographer, poet, novelist, musician, and filmmaker (circa 2004), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 10)
    - Ronald L. Freeman, long-time photographer for the Smithsonian Institute (2004), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 11)
    - James Allen, curator of lynching exhibit Without Sanctuary (2004), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 12)
    - Lynda Koolish, primary photographer and assembler of this quilt-like exhibit (2008), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 13)
    - Dennis Brutus (1924-2009) South African poet and imprisoned activist against apartheid (2008), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 14)
    - Sonia Sanchez, poet, educator, playwright, and Cave Canem Elder (2010), 2012 (Box OV4, Folder 15)
    - Lucille (Sayles) Clifton as a child (circa 1940), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 1)
    - Thelma Moore Sayles, Lucille's mother (1914-1959) (circa 1950), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 2)
    - Clifton Home 1967-1981, 2605 Talbot Road, Baltimore, Maryland (circa 1980), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 3)
    - Clifton Home 1981-1984, 2437 Pickwick Road, Dickeyville, Maryland (circa 1982), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 4)
    - Audre Lorde (1934-1992) poet, writer, and feminist visionary (1978), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 5)
    - Toi Derricotte, poet and co-founder of Cave Canem (2000), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 6)
    - Galway Kinnell, poet and presenter at the Squaw Valley Writers' Conference (1991), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 7)
    - Lucille Clifton, who received Lifetime Achievement Award at the 2004 Furious Flower Conference at JMU (2004, 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 8)
    - Patricia Smith, poet, activist, and Cave Canem Faculty (2004), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 9)
    - Toni Morrison, Nobel Laureate novelist, educator, and former editor at Random House (1987), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 10)
    - Gwendolyn Magee, quilter and Mississippi Institute of Arts and Letters Visual Artist of 2003 (2004), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 11)
    - Children of Philadelphia, Mississippi, heirs of the Civil Rights struggle of the 1960s (2004), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 12)
    - June Jordan (1936-2002) poet, playwright, and activist (1984), 2012 (Box OV5, Folder 13)
  - 2004-2005 Events, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)